Be calm!
（ミカエル）
静まれ！
Do not panic.
うろたえるな
それでも神々の先兵か
You call yourselves the vanguard of the gods?
ふん！
（ミカエル）
バハムートの復活の予兆だ
This is a harbinger of Bahamut's awakening.
You must make haste, maiden of Orléans, recipient of my light.
急ぐのだ
我が啓示を受けし
オルレアンの乙女よ
Saint Jeanne!
（ラヴァレイ）
聖女ジャンヌ！
Lavalley?
（ジャンヌ）
ラヴァレイか
These winds have cut off all
communication with the others.
この風では
分遣隊との連絡も ままなりません
Our only option is to wait until the storm calms.
ここで
収まるのを待つほかありますまい
（ジャンヌ）
ただの嵐ではない
This is no ordinary storm.
見よ
Observe!
（ラヴァレイ）
これは…
What does this mean?
Since the God Key was taken from holy ground,
（ジャンヌ）
聖域から“神の鍵”が失われ
the order between gods and
demons has been deteriorating.
神族と魔族のバランスが
崩れ始めている
The gods' majesty no longer graces us, then?
（ラヴァレイ）
神々のご威光が
行き届いておらぬと？
Perhaps not.
（ジャンヌ）
あるいは…
I'm waiting for sunrises again
Rise up, rise up, rise up
Let me see the sun
（カイザル）
ハア… 逃がさん
Rage of Bahamut
逃がさんぞ ファバロ
貴様… だけは
Rage of Bahamut
ハア…
People always say
"black or white," but the world is so gray
Even angels and demons were once the son of God I praise
temee no gen'in wa temee no naka kara
You're the catalyst for your own demise
zenbu hikurumete omae no saga
It's inherent to your being
kizuku koro ni wa mou you're in a coffin
But by the time you realize, you're in a coffin
It's too late if you want to do something
What the hell is wrong with me?
I can't remember what I wanted to be
Tick, tack, which is what I found
I can see the keys are scattered around
kono yoru ga aketemo nanika kawaru wake ja nee sa
Even though a new day dawns, nothing's gonna change
Yes, I know; yes, I know that I...
I'm the only one
who can save myself
I've never forgotten
All I wanna be is me
You will not escape...
I won't allow it, Favaro...
I refuse... to let you...
ファバロ～！
Favaro!
（アザゼル）
パズズめ よくやるよ
Curse you, Pazuzu. You're too good.
（ケルベロス）
先を越されるわけには
いかないもんね
We can't let him beat us to the punch!
Get away, guard dog. You stink.
（アザゼル）
貴様か 番犬
寄るな 犬臭い
失礼ね
うちの子たちは お散歩中よ
Back off! My little ones are on a walk right now!
貴様こそ 控えろ
ここは俺の城だ
You're the one who should back off. This is my castle.
堅いわね
What a stick-in-the-mud.
You're a former angel, all right.
さすがは元天使
We're back, woof!
（オス犬）
ただいまワン
（メス犬）
見つけたワン
We found 'em, woof!
Good work! Where are they?
あら ご苦労さん
They're on their way to the
foggy town of Nebelville, woof!
あいつらは霧の町ネブルビルに
向かってるワン
Oh?
ほう？
How long are we gonna leave 'em be?
（ケルベロス）
いつまで泳がせておくつもり？
“誰の差し金なのかを探れ”
Need I remind you that our orders are only to learn who they're working for?
そういう命令だったはずだ
Then let's just catch 'em and torture 'em, woof!
とっ捕まえて
拷問しちゃえばいいワン
（アザゼル）
そう慌てることもあるまいよ
There's no need for such rashness.
あの町には…
There happens to be a particularly
interesting individual in that town.
ちょっと面白いヤツがいるのでな
（ファバロ）
フウ…
Th-There's the town.
ま… 町だ
Is that Helheim?
（アーミラ）
あれがヘルヘイム？
Hell no!
Helheim is way, way further ahead! Way further!
ヘルヘイムは
もっと もっと もっと…
ずう～っと先！
（アーミラ）
じゃあ 早く行こう
Then let's get going!
（ファバロ）
待て待て
Whoa, hold on!
We need to get us some money first or we're gonna run dry.
ここらで ひと稼ぎしとかねえと
干上がっちまう
Let's see...
え～と
この辺りの賞金首っつうと…
What bounties can we get around here?
こいつだな
This'll do!
じゃあ 早く行こう！
Then let's get going!
Whoa! Hold your horses!
（ファバロ）
ちょ… ちょ 待て　待てって！
こいつは ちょいと…
This one's gonna be a real pain in the ass.
面倒な仕事になるぜ～
Nebelville
----------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Almost...
もうちょい…
どわっ！
Seriously?!
マジか？
Man!
たく…
どうなってんだ
What the hell?!
Running into a monster in broad daylight like this?
まっ昼間から こんなとこで
魔物に出くわすってよお
Damn.
Well, at least we got what we came for.
まっ 目的のもんは手に入ったし
（アーミラ）
私は肉のほうが好き
I prefer meat.
（ファバロ）
食うんじゃねえ！
These ain't for eating!
They're herbs. Our next target
supposedly knows restorative arts.
こいつはハーブだ
次の相手は医術の心得があるんだと
（アーミラ）イジュツ？
（ファバロ）医術！
Restorative?
Restorative.
Weird potions and all that.
（ファバロ）
妙な鼻薬(びやく)を使うらしい
We need to have some antidotes handy just in case.
だから 前もって
解毒剤を用意しとくんだよ
So we're not going to eat it?
（アーミラ）
あれは食べないの？
（ファバロ）
腹 壊すぞ…
Do you want to get sick?
Favaro!
ファバロ～！
ハア…
（リタ）
あら 生きてたの
Oh. You're alive.
（カイザル）
ここは…
Where am I?
（リタ）
折れてたから
It was broken.
（リタの父親）
おお 気が付かれましたか 騎士様
Oh, you're awake, Sir Knight!
（リタの母親）
お加減は いかがですか？
How are you feeling?
I work as a humble doctor here in Nebelville.
（リタの父親）
私は この町ネブルビルで
医師をやっております者
This is my wife,
こちらは妻と…
and this is our daughter, Rita.
そして 娘のリタ
（リタの母親）
さあ どうか こちらへ
Please, right this way.
（リタの父親）
お食事を ご用意いたしましたゆえ
We've prepared a meal for you.
Man, this stuff reeks.
（ファバロ）
くう～！　ひっでえにおい…
I just realized you have wings!
お前 羽 生えてんだからよ
ひとっ飛びすりゃあ
これ 取りに行けたろ！
You could've just flown up to get these!
I couldn't have.
（アーミラ）
それは無理
I lost one during the incident. I can't fly anymore.
あのとき 片方ちぎれちゃったから
もう飛べない
（ファバロ）
あのとき？
The incident?
The incident.
あのときだ…
（アーミラ）
これが…
This... is the God Key...
神の鍵
Lenes G'batha Org.
レネス･グバーザ･オーグ
Stop right there!
（騎士）
そこまでだ！
（ファバロ）
神の鍵？
God Key?
Yeah.
（ファバロ）
王都の騎士団が言ってたやつか
Is that what those knights were talkin' about?
We must retrieve the God Key!
（ゴラン）
盗まれた“神の鍵”を奪還するのだ
You're telling me you managed to swipe it all by yourself?
そいつを お前が
たった１人で かっぱらったって？
（アーミラ）
君… 信じてないな
You don't believe me?
（ミカエル）
だが 実際に それは起こったのだ
It did actually happen, however.
魔の者は決して
She infiltrated holy ground upon which a demon couldn't possibly tread...
足を踏み入れることができぬはずの
聖域に
あの娘は侵入し…
...broke the key's seal using arts only a god could possibly use...
神にしか決して使えぬはずの
秘術を用いて
鍵の封印を解き…
...and ran off with the key, just like that!
（ケルベロス）
まんまと鍵を奪って
逃げちゃったってわけね
（ファバロ）
だったら その神の鍵とやらは
今どこにある？
So then where's this so-called "God Key" now?
Here.
ここにある
Huh? Where? Let me s—
The key isn't a physical object.
鍵の本質は物体じゃない
ちいっ…
I took the key by absorbing its soul.
（アーミラ）
あのとき 私は
鍵の魂を私の中に取り込んだ
Which means that I'm now...
だから 今は私が…
あの娘自身が…
The girl herself is now...
神の鍵だ
...the God Key.
Our town is a meager one,
（リタの父親）
何もない町でして
大したおもてなしもできませんが
so I'm afraid we can't offer much hospitality.
Don't be. I'm very grateful that you came to my aid.
（カイザル）
とんでもない
危ないところを助けていただき
感謝します
この ご恩は…
I owe you—
I'm the one who brought you here.
（リタ）
拾ったのは私よ
Come, please eat. No need to
hold back for politeness' sake.
ささ 遠慮なさらず
どうか召し上がってください
（カイザル）
では…
Thank you.
The truth is, Sir Knight, we were
hoping we could ask you a favor.
実は騎士様
折り入って お願いがございまして
Of course.
（カイザル）
何なりと
Terrible monsters have been attacking our town.
この町は今
恐ろしい魔物に狙われているのです
Monsters?
魔物？
Trolls of sorts that live in the forest.
（リタの父親）
森に棲(す)みついたトロールの一種です
They come out at dawn to ravage our fields,
夜明けともに やって来て
畑を荒らし
eat our livestock,
家畜を食らい 子供をさらう
and take our children.
Rita is the only child left now.
もう 町の子供はリタ１人
But if this keeps up...
このままでは いずれ…
（カイザル）
ふむ…
（リタ）
フウ…
All right.
（カイザル）
分かりました
I, Kaisar, shall repay the favor you have shown me by slaying these detestable monsters for you.
このカイザル 必ずや
汚らわしい魔物を討ち果たし
恩義に報いてみせましょう
What's wrong, Rita? You haven't eaten.
（リタの母親）
どうしたの リタ？
食べてないじゃない
You expect me to eat this
putrid, maggot-filled muck?
こんな腐って ウジのわいた泥水
食べられるもんですか
（リタの父親）
リタ！
Rita!
Allow me.
（カイザル）
私が
You mustn't speak to your parents like that.
（カイザル）
ご両親に
あんなことを言ってはいけないな
Did you eat it?
（リタ）
あれを食べたの？
It brought back memories of meals with my own family.
（カイザル）
久しぶりに家庭の味を思い出したよ
You're going to regret it.
（リタ）
後悔するわよ
What about it did you not like?
何が そんなに気に入らない？
Everything.
（リタ）
何もかも
This is a pathetic farce. I'm sick of playing family.
くだらない茶番だわ こんなの
家族ごっこには もう うんざり
You're a philosophical one.
達観だな
リタといったか　年は？
Rita, was it? How old are you?
I forgot, but I'm most certainly older than you.
（リタ）
忘れたわ
あなたより年上なのは確かよ
I used to find my family annoying, as well.
私も かつては
家族を煩わしく思っていたものだ
I come from a longstanding family of knights, you see.
私の家は代々 騎士の家系でね
I had a strict upbringing,
having nary a moment to relax.
小さいころから厳しく しつけられ
気の休まる時もなかった
I loathed my stern father and spent most of my time away from home.
厳格な父を嫌い
家に寄りつかなかったこともある
Much like you do now.
ちょうど 今の君のように
But one day, when my father was tasked with guarding a tribute to the king,
だが あるとき
父が王への献上品の護衛の任を
仰せつかった折に
there was an incident.
事件は起こった
Bandits ambushed his unit and stole the tribute.
隊列が盗賊の急襲を受け
献上品を奪われてしまったのだ
My father, who had led the knights, was held responsible...
騎士団を率いていた父は
その責を問われ…
縛り首となった
and hanged.
The prestigious Lidfard family was
instantly stripped of its knighthood
栄光あるリドファルド家は
たちまち騎士の資格を剥奪(はくだつ)され
and banished to the lower quarters like criminals.
罪人のように城下を追われたよ
My mother wept every night after we lost everything,
何もかも失って
毎夜泣いていた母が
湖に身を投げたのは
until she cast herself into a lake half a year later.
その半年後だった
It was only then that I finally realized...
そのときになって ようやく…
分かった
how much I loved my family...
自分が いかに家族を愛し
支えられていたかを…
and how much it meant to me.
Don't be like me. Treasure your family while you still can!
失ってからでは遅い
君も私のように…
どわあ！
What a dull story. I shouldn't have bothered listening.
（リタ）
退屈な話ね　聞くんじゃなかったわ
The bathroom's that way.
（リタ）
トイレは あっちよ
Th-Thank you...
あ… ありがとう
They're coming.
来たか
Kaisar? What are you doing?
（トロール）
カイザル？　何やってんだ お前？
Do not speak my name freely, monster!
化け物が気安く私の名を呼ぶな！
Stand back.
お下がりを
ここは私一人で十分
I can handle this on my own!
There's what we're after!
（トロール）
そいつが元凶か
You'll go no further!
（カイザル）
させるか！
ふん！　たあっ！
What the hell?!
（トロール）
マジかよ！
（カイザル）
ふん！
うっ！　がはっ…
Custom-made with a special herb.
You wide awake now?
ハーブをすり込んだ特製だ
目え覚めたか？
Favaro! What have you done to me?!
ファバロ！
貴様 私に何をした？
Take a look around you.
周りを よく見ろ
The fog's gotten to your head.
お前 この霧に やられたんだよ
I wish you could've stayed oblivious.
ずっと気付かなければ
よかったのに
がはっ…
Rita the Necromancer, I assume?
（ファバロ）
ネクロマンサー･リタだな
Your twisted game ends now.
てめえの悪趣味な おままごとも
今日限りだ
How heartless. Let's play together.
つれないわね
一緒に遊びましょうよ
Thanks, but no thanks.
（ファバロ）
まっぴら御免こうむる
ゾンビと
ままごとを続けたくなければ
I suggest you use that unless you wanna keep playin' house with zombies!
それを使うんだな
折れてなど… いない
It's... not broken at all!
How dare you...
よくも…
How dare you make a fool out of me!
よくも たばかってくれたな！
いやああ！
ふん！　はあっ！
Man, he's scarier than the zombies.
（ファバロ）
ゾンビより おっかねえぜ…
There you are!
（カイザル）
そこにいたか！
リタ！
Rita?!
Damn you!
（カイザル）
バカ野郎！
That's it!
（ファバロ）
そいつだ！
Seel Soh Cetom!
（ファバロ）
シール･ソー･ケトム
The Black Bible. This is what we're really after.
ブラックバイブル…
本命は こいつさ
Monsters apparently invaded Nebelville some two hundred years ago, so it's long gone now.
このネブルビルは
200年も前に魔物に襲われて
とっくに滅んでたんだと
The only survivor, the daughter of the town doctor,
だが たった１人生き残った
町医者の娘が
used a sorcery book she found somewhere to revive the dead.
どっかから手に入れた魔導書で
死者を よみがえらせた
She's been at this twisted game for the past two hundred years.
それから200年間
ずっと このイカレた茶番を
続けてたってわけだ
I'm sick of playing family.
（リタ）
家族ごっこには もう うんざり
She's been bitten by a zombie,
so she'll turn into one as well soon.
（ファバロ）
その娘はゾンビに かまれた
放っておいたら
ゾンビになっちまうぜ
Not my problem, though.
まっ
俺の知ったことじゃねえけどな
Here ya go. 750 Rupies.
（バッカス）
ほらよ 750ルピ
That's it?
（ファバロ）これっぽっちかよ
（アーミラ）お～い 待て！
Hey, wait!
Hey! Don't eat him!
（ファバロ）
おい 食うんじゃねえぞ
That reminds me. These ones came in recently.
（バッカス）
そういや
こんなもんが回ってきてたなあ
Oh, new posters?
（ファバロ）
ん？　新しい手配書か？
Wh-Whoa!
て… おい！
Oh, yes. I still have more.
（バッカス）
ああ そうだ まだ ここにも…
See?
ほら
世ん中にゃあ
よく似た面の人間がいるもんで…
It's crazy how everyone's got lookalikes out there.
Oh, yes. You wanna go to Helheim, I hear.
（バッカス）
そうそう
ヘルヘイムに行きたいんだってなあ
Yeah, yeah. I wanna go to Hel—
そうそう
ヘルヘイムに行きたいんだって…
They got some of the finest,
tastiest booze there, y'know.
あそこには
とびきりうまい酒があんだよ
My destiny,
sotto oshiete hoshii
won't you tell me?
aenai
But you're gone
ima wa tooi place to be
in a place so far away
hitoribocchi todokanai
Alone and never-reaching
oshietekureta the truth is free
That's what you told me, and now the truth is free
I miss you
I revere you
You're my everything
I will follow you
subete wa ano toki
It all began then
You're my destiny
tsuretette
So take me
yakusoku no basho e
to the promised land
You're walking too fast.
（リタ）
歩くの早すぎ
少しは加減しなさいよ
Slow down a little, will you?
I never asked you to follow me!
（カイザル）
貴様が勝手に
ついてきているだけだ
You're supposed to respect the dead, you know.
（リタ）
死人は いたわるものよ
This is why I can't stand whippersnappers.
これだから若造は
ハア…
好きにしろ
Suit yourself.
Why didn't you just lop my head off?
（リタ）
どうして
首を斬り落とさなかったの？
I can't cut the dead. It would taint my sword.
（カイザル）
死者は斬らん　剣に穢(けが)れが付く
You had no problem cutting up my zombies, though.
（リタ）
私のゾンビは
斬りまくってたじゃない
Don't lump the dead and the undead together.
（カイザル）
アンデッドと死者を 一緒にするな
I think everyone's starting to realize.
（カイザル）
そろそろ
みんな 気付いてるんじゃないか？
（ファバロ）
何が？
Realize what?
That these previews aren't that serious.
（カイザル）
この予告が適当なんじゃないかって
（ファバロ）
そうか？
You think so?
On the next Rage of Bahamut: Genesis,
"Reunion at Ysmenport."
（２人）
次回「神撃(しんげき)のバハムート GENESIS(ジェネシス)」
Reunion(リユニオン) at(アット) Ysmenport(イースマンポート)
Yes!
（ファバロ）
イエス！
Illustration: